Finding Aid for Ypsilanti Kiwanis Club records, 1921-1986
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ypsilanti Kiwanis Club records 1921-1986
Ypsilanti Kiwanis Club.
1 linear foot
921109 Bk 2
Ypsilanti, Michigan chapter of the Kiwanis Clubs. Historical information and club bylaws, monthly and annual reports, minutes of meetings, membership files, publications, scrapbook and clippings, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by the Ypsilanti Kiwanis Club (Donor No. 7941 ) in 1991.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Ypsilanti Kiwanis Club, chartered in 1921, is the 15th oldest Kiwanis club in the Michigan district. Since its founding, the Club has been involved in numerous community service and charitable activities. The activities of the Club have changed over the years to meet community needs, but some of the projects have included providing funds for medical care for children, vocational guidance programs, organizing park clean-up projects, church support programs, and the formation of Key Clubs. During the 1920s, the Club was especially involved in rural school supervision, and was instrumental in the establishment of the Lincoln consolidated school district. During World War II the Club became involved with bond purchasing and raised funds for the purchase of a washer for the Willow Run Air Base. In the 1950s much emphasis was placed on sponsoring children to attend Scout Jamborees, summer camps and Interlochen music camp, but the Kiwanis also remained active in issues of national and community interest. The late 1950s and the 1960s saw a rise in park clean-up projects. Fund raising to support these activities is a major part of the Kiwanis organization, and over the years many creative ideas have been employed to raise money, such as rummage sales, pancake breakfasts and chicken dinners.
The Ypsilanti Kiwanis Club Records are comprised of historical information and bylaws; monthly and annual reports which document the membership, activities and financial transactions of the organization; meeting minutes; membership information; Ypsilanti Kiwanis publications; scrapbooks, newspaper clippings, and photographs. The monthly reports cover the years 1957-1983, but there is a considerable gap for the early 1970s. Annual audit reports were compiled by the Club's budget committee and itemize the expenses and money raised by the Club through dues and fund raising. There are many gaps in the audit reports, which cover the period of the 1940s and 1950s. Several other annual reports are in the collection, such as the Club Achievement report, the Club report and an Activity Survey. The different titles and formats reflect the changing forms over the years. Unfortunately, these annual reports are very spotty, with only a few years' records being preserved. Club elections are recorded in the Annual Club Election file; there is again, however, a gap for the late 1960s and 1970s reports.
Minutes of the Club meetings document the weekly decisions and concerns of the organization between the founding in 1921 and 1986. The names and occupations of club members are located in the Club Roster files. Two newsletters are found in the publications series - the Kiwanis News and We are the Kiwanis of Ypsilanti. The scrapbook and photograph series reflect the community service activities of the Club.
Subjects:
Social service--Michigan--Ypsilanti--Societies, etc.; Thrift shops--Michigan--Ypsilanti.; Ypsilanti (Mich.); Ypsilanti Kiwanis Club.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Laborers.; Parks--Michigan--Ypsilanti.; Playgrounds--Michigan--Ypsilanti.; Ypsilanti (Mich.); Ypsilanti Kiwanis Club.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Organizational records
  - Historical Information (Box 1)
  - Club Bylaws (Box 1)
  - Reports
    - Monthly
      - 1957 (Box 1)
      - 1958 (Box 1)
      - 1959 (Box 1)
      - 1960 (Box 1)
      - 1961 (Box 1)
      - 1962 (Box 1)
      - 1963 (Box 1)
      - January 1964 (Box 1)
      - 1965 (Box 1)
      - October-December 1977 (Box 1)
      - 1978 (Box 1)
      - 1979 (Box 1)
      - 1980 (Box 1)
      - 1981 (Box 1)
      - 1982 (Box 1)
      - January-September 1983 (Box 1)
    - Annual
      - Audit Reports (Box 1)
      - Club Achievement Reports 1958-1959 (Box 1)
      - Club Report 1976-1977, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
      - Activity Survey 1952-1955 (Box 1)
      - Reports of Club Election
        - 1932-1964 (Box 1)
        - 1981-1984 (Box 1)
  - Minutes
    - 1921-1925 (Box 1)
    - 1926-1930 (Box 1)
    - 1931-1935 (Box 1)
    - 1936-1940 (Box 1)
    - 1941-1945 (Box 1)
    - 1946-1950 (Box 1)
    - 1951-1955 (Box 1)
    - 1956-1960 (Box 1)
    - 1961-1965 (Box 1)
    - 1966-1970 (Box 1)
    - 1971-1975 (Box 1)
    - 1976-1980 (Box 1)
    - 1981-1983 (Box 1)
  - Membership Information
    - Club Roster
      - 1921-1939 (Box 1)
      - 1940-1949 (Box 1)
      - 1950-1959 (Box 1)
      - 1960-1986 (Box 1)
    - Membership of African Americans 1950 (Box 1)
  - Publications
    - Kiwanis News
      - 1950 (Box 1)
      - 1971-1975 (Box 1)
      - 1976-1987 (Box 1)
    - We are the Kiwanis of Ypsilanti 1983-1987 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook
    - Harold Beadle 1950 (Box 1)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 1)
  - Photographs
    - Ardis School Project (Box 1)
    - Park Project 1958 (Box 1)
    - Photo album February 18, 1987 (Box 1)